Dalek nine complete.
Dalek-九号-完成
Check.
检查通过
We are the new race of Daleks!
(我们-是-新一代-Daleks!)
Dalek ten complete.
Dalek-十号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek eleven complete.
Dalek-十一号-完成
Dalek twelve complete.
Dalek-十二号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek thirteen complete.
Dalek-十三号-通过
Dalek fourteen complete.
Dalek-十四号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek fifteen complete.
Dalek-十五号-完成
Dalek sixteen complete.
Dalek-十六号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek seventeen complete.
Dalek-十七号-完成
Dalek eighteen complete.
Dalek-十八号-完成
What's the matter? What is it?
怎么回事, 这是干什么?
Are you ill?
你生病了吗?
They're in there - making themselves! Duplicating!
它们在里面 - 制造它们自己! 在复制!
What? What are you talking about?
什么? 你在说什么?
I started this, opening the capsule!
是我挑起的, 打开了太空舱!
Lesterson!
Lesterson!
Don't try to stop me!
别想阻止我!
What happened?
发生了什么?
They forget that I control them! I gave them life back again, and now I've taken it away! Finished! Stopped it!
它们忘记了是该由我控制! 我重新给了它们生命复活了它们, 现在我要拿走! 结束他们! 阻止它们!
The Daleks...
那些 Daleks...
Evil! Horrible! I know what I'm going to do! Laser torches! Melt them down! I'm going to melt the Daleks down to pools of metal!
邪恶! 恐怖! 我知道我要干什么了! 激光束! 把他们融掉! 我要把这些 Daleks 融化为金属池!
You won't Lesterson!
你不会的 Lesterson!
Ah, do you think I care what you can do?! Go on, tell everybody I was responsible for Resno's death! I don't care! I'm going to wipe out the Daleks!
啊, 你觉得我还顾忌你能做什么?! 去吧, 告诉每一个人是我害死了Resno! 我不在乎! 我要抹平这些 Daleks!
Yes, tell everybody all about me! I'm still going to... I'm going to... wipe out the Daleks!
是的, 告诉每一个人我的事. 我还是要...我要... 抹掉这些 Daleks!
Get me the Examiner. Prison? Who put him there? But I've got to talk to him! I've got to, don't you understand?!
给我接监察员. 狱警? 谁把他关进去的. 但我要跟他谈话! 我必须要, 听不懂吗?!
How did you get there?! I cut off the power!
你怎么过来的?! 我已经把电源切断了!
We can store power. We will soon have our own.
我们-可以-储存-能量 我们-很快-会有-自己的-能量
Own power?!
自己的能量?!
Why was the capsule door closed?
为什么-舱门-关闭了
Own power?! Ahh!
自己的能量?! 啊!
Seal off the capsule's secret entrance.
封闭-舱体-秘密-入口
I obey.
我-服从
Wait!
等!
No more than three Daleks to be seen together at any one time.
每次-不要-三个-以上-Daleks-同时-出现-被人-看到
I obey.
我-服从
We are not ready yet to teach these human beings the law of the Daleks.
我们-还没-打算-教导-这些-人类-学习-Daleks-的法律
You can help me!
你可以帮我!
What's the matter?
什么事情?
Where... where's the Examiner?! I _?!
监察员... 监察员在哪儿?! 我...
The Examiner's in prison.
监察员在监狱里
Ah, yes.
啊, 是的
What's the matter with you?
你怎么回事?
I forgot.
我忘了...
What are you running for? Hey!
为什么跑? 嘿!
Did Lesterson come back?
Lesterson 回来了吗?
No. Why is this human restricted?
没有. 为什么-这个人-被-限制-自由?
She's against the Daleks.
她反对 Daleks.
Afraid, are you? Nothing's going to happen to you if you behave.
害怕了, 是吧? 如果你乖乖地话就什么事情也没有
The Daleks? Of course I'm afraid - and so should you be.
Daleks? 我当然害怕 - 你也应该害怕
The Daleks are going to help us.
Daleks 将要帮助我们
'Us' being the rebels, I suppose.
“我们”是指叛乱分子吧, 没说错的话
If you like.
随你便.
And when you've won, the Daleks will just go back to being servants again? You're bigger fools than I thought.
而且如果你们赢了的话, Daleks 会回来继续当仆人? 你们比我想的还要蠢
We are your servants.
我们-是-你们的-仆人
While it suits you.
While it suits you.
You'll see.
走着瞧
In!
进去!
you want me to stay with her?
你想要我留这里看着她吗?
Yes. You may have to help Valmar. He'll be here in a minute to fix up the new Dalek cower... power cable.
是的. 你可能还得帮一下 Valmar. 他马上过来, 来修 Dalek 需要的新电缆
Right.
好.
When will the work be completed?
什么-时候-这项-工作-完成?
What is this cable you Daleks are laying, anyway?
你们 Daleks 在铺设的这是什么线缆?
Daleks operate on static electricity.
Daleks-需要-静电-才能-运转
Static! Is that possible?
静电! 这可能吗?
To create static, the Daleks need a complete cable circuit.
为了-制造-静电  Daleks-需要-完整的-线缆-回路
I see. You convert our electricity into your own power.
我明白了. 你把我们对我电能转换成了你们的能量
That is correct. When will the human being complete the work?
正确   什么-时候-这人-可以-完成-这项-工作?
He'll be here. It's easier now. There's no-one to interfere with our plans.
他马上就来了. 现在比较容易了, 没有人干涉我们的计划了
Do you have to do that? I'm afraid you'll find these locks are foolproof.
你必须做这个吗? 恐怕你会发现这些锁普通人是打不开的
I wonder how they're converting the power?
我很好奇他们是怎么转换能量的
Wha... What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊...?
The Daleks - they're powered by static electricity. It's like blood to them - a constant life-stream.
Daleks - 它们是依赖静电供能的, 静电就像它们的血液一样 - 一种持续的生命流
Static isn't workable!
静电没法使用啊!
It is to the Daleks. They've conquered static, just as they've conquered anti-magnetics.
对 Daleks 来说是可用的. 他们已经征服了静电, 正如他们征服了反磁场一样
I'm not going to listen to any more of this nonsense.
我不打算继续听这些胡说八道了
I don't seem to be able to hit the right note.
似乎我总没法发出正确的声调
Do you have any more water?
你那儿还有水吗?
I hope not. No.
我期望没有. 没有
Then I shall have to get some.
那我就得再搞点
You can't!
你没办法!
But it's important! It's desperately important!
但这很重要! 已经穷途陌路了!
Well, Bragen gave orders.
Bragen 下了命令了
Just get out of my way!
别挡我的道
Ah! Examiner! The Daleks...!
啊, 监察员, 那些 Daleks
Yes?
怎么了?
They're duplicating! I've seen them!
他们在复制! 我都看见了!
They've got their own power now! I... I can't stop them!
它们现在有自己的能力了! 我没法阻止它们
Take him to Bragen.
把他带到 Bragen 那里去
Oh!... Oh!... Oh!...
噢... 噢... 噢...
I say. I say, do you think we might have a little more water?
听我说, 你觉得可否再给我们一点水?
Is that all you can say? Lesterson fights his way down here to speak to you and all you can do is demand more water?!
你能说的就是这个? Lesterson 好不容易跑进来跟你情况, 你就只是再要一点水?
Get away from the door.
离门远一点
Sorry about that outburst. I thought it might help the situation.
抱歉刚才发飙了, 我也是期望有所帮助
Nearly... Nearly...
快了, 快了
What's this?
这是什么情况?
He tried to break in and speak with the Examiner.
他试图闯入监狱, 跟监察员说话
What is the Dalek doing?!
这个 Dalek 在干什么?!
I thought you knew. Something to do with the emergency power supply.
我以为你知道. 好像是应急电源什么的
Ah, no! It's... it's a trick! I didn't ask for it!
啊, 不! 这是... 这是个伎俩! 我没有要求安装这个!
Lesterson, I've had reports.
Lesterson, 我都收到报告了.
What are you doing?!
你在做什么?!
Laying the new emergency power supply as you ordered, master.
执行-你的-命令-铺设-应急-电源. 主人
It... it... it's a lie!
这... 这是个谎言!
I've had reports of your incomprehensible behaviour.
我已经收到报告了, 说的就是你出现了一些不可理喻的行为
Yes. Yes, I... I can explain - if you'll get rid of that!
是的. 是的, 我... 我能解释 - 不过你得把那东西赶开!
Finish now.
结束吧
I am your servant.
我-是-你的-仆人
Where is the Governor?!
总督在哪里?!
At the perimeter. Why?
在下面巡视呢. 问这个干什么?
Call him! Get him back here as quickly as possible! We're all in terrible danger! The Examiner was right! Right all the time!
给他打电话! 让他尽快赶回来! 我们现在处于可怕的危险当中! 监察员当初是对的! 一直都是对的!
Don't listen to anything she has to say!
别听她要说的任何话!
Come along now.
过来吧
She's in league with the Daleks!
她跟 Daleks 是一伙的!
Now, now, now, now. Please, Lesterson. Let's just take things calmly, you're not well.
现在, 现在, Lesterson. 我们冷静一点处理, 你现在看起来不太好
I'm perfectly well!
我好得不能太好了!
Please Lesterson, please. Now, you ought to be in hospital. You promised me you'd report there.
打住 Lesterson, 打住. 现在, 你应该在医院待着. 你答应我你到那里后向我报告
I promised nothing of the kind!
我才不答应这样的事情!
Don't you remember? Never mind. I understand.
你难道不记得了? 算了. 我理解
Hmm. Pity. It's probably only temporary.
唔. 遗憾. 期望只是暂时的
You're trying to say I'm mad!
你是想说我疯了!
No. No, not mad.
呵呵, 不不, 不是疯了
No. Of course not. No.
不是. 当然不是
But, I tell you, I saw the Daleks! They were duplicating! I saw it! I swear to you!
不过我告诉你, 我看见了, Daleks 在自我复制! 我看见了! 我发誓!
He suddenly started saying these things in the lab. I'm... I'm afraid, he's...
他突然就开始在实验室说这些胡言乱语. 我... 我怕他是..
Oh, no! No!
噢, 不 ! 不!
Keep him under restraint.
看住他吧.
Oh, will nobody listen to me?!
噢, 没有人听进去我的话?!
I can't. My hands are tied. Anyway, I wouldn't help you, even if I could.
我做不到. 我的手被捆住了 .  再说了, 即使我能做到, 我也不会帮你
OK.
OK.
More? I can't handle them.
还有? 我都干不过来了
This is the lot.
那是你的份额
Listen. The Dalek's gone now.
听.  Dalek 已经走了
That doesn't mean you can start talking.
那并不意味着你可以说话了
Oh, leave her alone, Kebble. She isn't doing any harm.
噢, 让她一边待着, Kebble. 她不会有什么危害
You think you're very tough don't you, pushing a girl around. I'd like to see you come up against a real man.
你以为你是个硬汉吗? 不是, 也就能把一个女孩推来推去. 我倒期望你像个硬汉一样站出来
Like who?
比如说谁?
Like Ben, for instance.
比如说 Ben
Don't worry about him. We've got him safely stowed away.
别替他操心了. We've got him safely stowed away.
You've got Ben?
你们抓了 Ben?
He's sleeping off a slight fall.
他可得好好睡一觉.
I told you to leave her alone.
我跟你说了让她一边待着
Your name's Valmar, isn't it?
你的名字是 Valmar, 对吧?
That's it.
不假
You want the Daleks to fight the Governor. But don't you see? They'll turn on you, too.
你想要让 Daleks 去跟总督斗但你看不出来吗, 它们也会攻击你们的
What? Three big pepper pots?
什么? 那三个胡椒小罐?
One of them did kill Resno. You saw what the Dalek did to that sheet of metal.
其中一个把 Resno 杀死了. 你们也都看到了 Dalek 对着金属板开火是什么场景
And that's just the beginning.
而且那还只是个开始
Don't listen to her. She's giving you the Examiner's line.
别听她的, 她要把你带到监察员那个阵营
He isn't the Examiner. We're just travellers. Landed here by accident. The Doctor - that's the man you think is the Examiner - found the real Examiner dead, and picked up his papers.
他不是监察员. 我们只是旅行者, 因为故障降落在这里了.
This Doctor of yours. He knows something about the Daleks?
你们的这个博士, 他知道 Daleks 的一些情况?
He tried to warn everyone. It's the only reason we stayed here.
他试图警告每一个人. 这是我们留在这里的唯一原因
When will the work be completed?
什么-时候-干完-这个?
I don't know. I'll need a new junction box like this one.
我不知道. 我需要连接盒, 跟这个类似的
You've all underestimated these Daleks.
你们全都低估了这些个 Daleks.
Better brains than us, I suppose.
大脑比我们厉害, 我估计
I only know what the Doctor has told me - he says they're capable of exterminating whole nations.
我只知道一些博士告诉我的 - 他说它们能够终结整个文明
Perhaps, but what would they want to kill us for - after we've taken over. We're friendly with the Daleks.
也许吧, 但在我们接管之后, 它们杀死我们有什么好处呢 - 我们对 Daleks一直很友好
But, don't you see? Human beings can't be friends with Daleks. They don't have friends.
但你没看出来? 人类不可能跟 Daleks 做朋友. 它们没有朋友
I don't see why not.
我不明白为什么不能
It's a kind of hatred for anything unlike themselves. They think they're superior.
它们有一种仇恨, 仇恨任何跟它们不一样的东西. 它们认为它们更高级
The girl's got something.
这女孩说的有些道理
You want to tell Janley? You're welcome!
你想要告诉 Janley 吗? 欢迎你来!
Janley! She'll betray the lot of you, if she gets the chance.
Janley! 她一有机会就会背叛你们中的大多数
The other junction box is outside.
另一个-连接盒-在-外面
Thank you.
谢谢你
Talk too much, don't you? Didn't you know he was soft on Janley?
太多话了, 是吧? 你不知道说到 Janley 他心肠就软了
All right, all right, I'm just putting her straight.
没事, 没事, 我只是不想让她走向邪路.
More slack on the cables.
电缆方面我们进展太慢了
What are all these cables lying about?
到处布的这些都是什么线缆?
New emergency power supply.
新的应急供电线路
Who's idea was that?
那是谁的主意?
What do you want to know for?
你想知道这个干什么?
What do I...?! Don't you know I'm the Governor?
我要知道...?! 你不知道我是总督?
Where are you from?
你从哪里来的?
The interior, sir.
内务部, 先生
The interior? Why are you carrying a gun?
内务部? 为什么带枪?
I'm a Squad Leader in Bragen's guard, sir.
我是 Bragen 安保小队的队长, 先生
Oh, I see. Bragen's guard, eh? All right, carry on.
哦, 明白了. Bragen 的保安, 嗯? 好吧, 继续拿着吧.
Cut that row out, you two!
Cut that row out, 你们俩!
Stop that.
停下.
Oh!
噢!
Come on.
Come on.
Wait a minute!
等一下!
We don't want him trying it, although he seemed a bit tone deaf to me.
我可不想让他也来尝试这个方法 - 虽然他看起来也不像是个懂音调的人
Well, Bragen - these trips are becoming more and more demanding.
唉, Bragen - 这一趟趟的似乎越来越吃力了
I didn't expect you, Governor.
没想到你会出现, 总督
Ah, I had as much as I could stand. Well? What's been happening here?
啊, 再往外跑我就有点受不了了. 怎么样? 这里发生了什么?
One moment.
等会儿.
I asked you a question, man.
我问你问题呢, 伙计.
I heard you.
我听见了.
Look, your work can wait. You can hand over to me tomorrow. I want to hear about the Examiner.
嘿, 你的工作可以先放放. 明天转交回我就行了. 我想听听监察员的情况.
The Examiner is at present in jail.
监察员目前在监狱里.
In jail? That's rather dangerous isn't it? Who put him there?
在监狱? 这样很危险, 不是吗? 谁把他投进去的?
I did.
我干的.
You did? In heaven's sake, why?
你干的? 天啦, 为什么?
He's an impostor, Governor. Possibly a murderer as well. We have just discovered the body of the real Examiner in the mercury swamp.
他是个假冒的, 总督. 还很可能是个谋杀犯. 我们刚在水银沼泽里面发现了真监察员的尸体.
I hope you're sure of your facts, Bragen.
我期望你说的情况都是事实, Bragen.
Quite sure.
相当确定.
This could have far-reaching consequences.
这可能会有长远的后果.
As far as I am concerned, there's nothing more to be said. So if there's nothing further...
就我所知, 这没什么需要补充的了. 如果没有其它事情...
Nothing further! Who the devil do you think you're talking to? Stand up when you're speaking to me man!
没有其它! 你以为你在跟谁说话? 跟我说话的时候站起来!
I prefer to remain seated.
我更愿意继续坐着.
Do you now?! We'll soon see about that. Guards!
是吗?! 我们就来看看. 保安!
Take this man out of my office.
把这个人带出我的办公室.
Did you hear what I said? That's an order!
你们没有听见我说的吗? 这是命令!
You forget, my dear Hensell. They're not your guards - they're mine.
你忘记了, 我亲爱的 Hensell. 他们不是你的保安 - 他们是我的.
I am the Governor!
我是总督!
No. Not now. I am.
不. 现在不是了. 我才是.
Oh, I see. Your guards, eh? Yes, Quinn warned me about your guards, but we all took them too lightly, didn't we? But we'll soon change that.
哦, 我明白了. 你的保安, 呃? 是了, Quinn 警告过我关于你的保安的事情, 但我们都没太重视? 不过我们很快可以纠正过来.
You imbecile! How long do you think your handful of guards can hang out when the people hear that I am being kept a prisoner in my own capital?!
你这个蠢人! 如果人们听说我在自己的首府被囚禁起来了, 你那几个保安还能自由多久?!
The people will do exactly as they are told, Hensell.
他们只会按照我们告诉他们的情况做出反应, Hensell.
It will, of course, be easier for them if you co-operate with us.
当然, 如果你与我们合作的话, 事情会更容易一点.
Wait there. Guards, dismissed.
等着. 保安, 你们可以出去了.
So Bragen, you want my co-operation, do you?
怎样, Bragen, 你需要我的合作, 对吧?
It would save bloodshed. I might even let you keep the title of Governor.
这样能少流些血. 我甚至可以让你继续留着总督的头衔.
Might you now?! I'll tell you what you will do. You'll order your guards to disarm and place yourself under arrest immediately!
你会吗?! 我来告诉你你将会做什么. 你让你的保安都解除武装, 立即逮捕你自己!
So you reject my offer? I thought it a generous one in the circumstances.
这么说你拒绝我的提议? 我还觉得在当前情形下这是个挺慷慨的提议呢.
What circumstances?
当前什么情形?
Look at this.
看看这个.
What is it?
这是什么?
The reason that the colony is now mine.
这就是为什么这个基地现在是我的.
Is it a weapon of some kind?
这是某种武器?
I'll arrange a demonstration for you. Do you still refuse my offer?
我给你安排一个演示吧. 你还是拒绝我的提议吗?
I will not be intimidated.
我不会妥协的.
Of course not. In character to the last, Hensell. Kill him!
当然不. 执迷不悟啊, Hensell. 杀了他!
Why do human beings kill human beings?
为什么-人类-杀死-人类?
Get on with your work!
去干你的活去!
Yes, master. I obey.
是的-主人  我-服从.
Yes, obey me! From now on, I will have complete obedience from everyone!
是的, 服从我! 从现在开始, 我要每个人都要绝对服从!
I'll have to check the cable circuit now. Otherwise, it's just as you asked for.
现在我还得检查一下线缆回路. 否则的话, it's just as you asked for.
Very well.
很-好.
Why can't you carry on with the power you're drawing from the colony? Why go to all this trouble?
为什么你们不直接利用你从基地抽取到的能量呢? 费这个劲做什么?
Until now, we have had to recharge from the colony supply. With static power, the Daleks will be twice as useful.
到目前-为止, 我们-还是-要用-基地-电力-充电. 采用-静电, Daleks-将会-加倍-有用.
Valmar, quick!
Valmar, 快点!
What's the matter?
怎么回事?
The Governor's back.
总督回来了.
What about the girl?
这女孩儿怎么办?
Leave her.
别管她了.
I will follow you.
我-要-跟着-你.
What for?
为什么?
I am your servant.
我-是-你的-仆人.
Come on.
得了吧.
An electrical circuit of their own supplying static electricity! I wonder how much longer we've got?
他们自己的静电供电线路! 我好奇我们还有多少时间?
I didn't realise they'd have a circuit of their own.
我没有意识到他们将有自己的供电线路.
Doctor, look out!
Doctor, 快看!
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
Well done! Who was the man who went outside just now?
做得好! 刚才出去的那个人是谁?
Valmar. He's been working for the Daleks.
Valmar. 他一直在给 Daleks 干活.
On their static power supply.
搭建他们的静电供应系统.
Doctor, they've got Ben.
Doctor, 他们抓了 Ben.
Yes, I know. He ran away so that I could... Oh well, it's a long story, but don't worry. That boy can take care of himself!
是的, 我知道. 他跑出来是为了让我... 噢, 算了, 说来话长, 不过别担心. 那小子可以照顾他自己!
Did you hear that? That won't help.
你听到了吗? That won't help.
Get out! All of you!
出去! 你们全部!
What about you?!
你怎么办?!
But Doctor! Oh...
但是, 博士! 噢...
Go!
走!
Have they escaped?
他们-逃跑-了吗?
Yes, return to capsule and report.
是的-回到-舱内-然后-报告.
I obey.
我-服从.
We are to wait here until the human beings fight among themselves.
我们-在-这里-等待-直到-人类-自己-内部-打起来.
Then we will strike.
然后-我们-将会-攻击.
And exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
然后-Exterminate（终结）! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! ...
The one man who could have saved us.
一个来可以救我们的人.
Don't worry, the people will follow you, too.
别担心, 人们也会跟随你的.
Maybe. But there wasn't any maybe about Hensell. He was old-fashioned. Single-minded, yes, but he's done a lot of wonderful work for this colony. Events turned out against him, that's all. But why? Why was he killed?
也许吧. 但 Hensel 没有太多 there wasn't any maybe about Hensell.
I can answer that.
我能回答这个.
He wanted to destroy the Daleks, so one of them killed him. Now, I'm declaring martial law. You will be returned to prison, and properly guarded this time.
他想要销毁 Daleks, 所以其中一个就杀死了他. 现在, 我宣布戒严令. 你将返回监狱, 这次会被好好看守住.
Martial law! What good do you think that will do against the Daleks?
戒严令! What good do you think that will do against the Daleks?
The Daleks will do as I tell them.
Daleks 将按我说的做.
We shall see, shan't we.
We shall see, shan't we.
Take them away.
把他们带走.
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
Exterminate (终结) ! Exterminate! Exterminate!
Orders received. Exterminate all humans!
指令-已收到. 消灭所有人类!
Exterminate all humans!
消灭所有人类!
Exterminate! Annihilate! Destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy!
Exterminate (终结)! 灭绝! 摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁!
Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy!
Daleks-征服-并摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁!